Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 182)
  - "Socinianism: An Approach to Human Rights,", undated (Box-folder 184: 4)
  - "John Milton: Father of the Bill of Rights,", undated (Box-folder 184: 5)
  - "The Emerging United Planet Earth,", undated (Box-folder 184: 6)
  - "Prostitution of the Constitution: ERA Extension 8 D.C. Senate Representation,", undated (Box-folder 184: 7)
  - "Home Pace: International Psycho-Socio-Politics,", undated (Box-folder 184: 8)
  - "Israel: The Rampart of American Security,", undated (Box-folder 184: 9)
  - "A President's Right to His Records: Fact, Not Hysteria,", undated (Box-folder 184: 10)
  - "A Presidential Power: A Profile for Dictatorship,", undated (Box-folder 184: 11)
  - "World Man and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 184: 12)
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", undated (Box-folder 184: 13)
  - "Habeas Corpus in International Law,", undated (Box-folder 184: 14)
  - "Our Extra Constitutional Census,", undated (Box-folder 184: 15)
  - Grant proposal from Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 184: 16-17)
    Includes related materials
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 185)
  - "International Terrorism: The Inversion of Relegated Responsibility,", undated (Box-folder 185: 1)
  - "The Emerging United Planet Earth,", undated (Box-folder 185: 2)
  - "A Preponderance of Perjury: The Continuing Farce of the Expert Witness,", undated (Box-folder 185: 3)
  - "Due Process of Economy: Anti-Trust Control of Agricultural Cooperatives,", undated (Box-folder 185: 4)
  - "Lincoln the Lawyer: Myth and Reality,", undated (Box-folder 185: 5)
  - "Christmas as a Legal Holiday: In Violation of the 1st Amendment,", undated (Box-folder 185: 6)
  - "Timocracy: The Inalienable Right to Self Respect,', undated (Box-folder 185: 7)
  - "Homo Pace: International Psycho-Socio-Politics,", undated (Box-folder 185: 8)
  - "Habeas Foeta: Due Process for the Unborn,", undated (Box-folder 185: 9)
  - "The Corruption of Wealth: Views of Aristotle, Plato, and St. Thomas Aquinas,", undated (Box-folder 185: 10)
  - "Presidential Executive Orders--Government by Fiat or Operational Necessity: An Expanding Definition,", undated (Box-folder 185: 11)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 185: 12)
- Randolph Ringstad--Miscellany, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 186: 1-18)
- Randolph Ringstad--Miscellany, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 187: 1-12)
- Randolph Ringstad--Miscellany, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 188: 1-21)
  Includes 11 photographic prints depicting him, his apartments, tennis court, and security light
- Caro A. Martin--India vs. U.S.A., 1979-1981 (Box-folder 189: 1-9)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, letters, and notes
- Armenia--Miscellany
  - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 189: 10-12)
  - 1982-1984 (Box-folder 190: 1-11)
  - 1974-1985 (Box-folder 191: 1-4)
- Global Pictures Corporation--Fred A. Niles, 1981-1984 (Box-folder 191: 5)
  Clippings, correspondence, and printed matter, and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 191: 6-7)
- Global Pictures Corporation--Fred A. Niles and W. Dean Rosenberg, 1981 and undated (Box-folder 192: 1-6)
  Clippings, correspondence, financial records, memoranda, printed matter, report, and miscellany
- Crystal Gibson Doyle vs. Thompson 8 McKinnon Auchincloss Inc., Howard Redding, Electronic Stock Evaluator Corporation, Robert W. Fischer and John Lambert, 1973 (Box-folder 193: 1)
- Anti-trust complaint, 1977-1979? (Box-folder 193: 2)
- Leo Kassin (Lake Communications Inc.), ICC Chicago Co., Allways International, and others, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 193: 3-26)
- Printed matter-- Korean Trade News, 1980 (Box-folder 193: 27)
- Luis Kutner vs. Guerra, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 194: 1-15)
- Synanon Corporation vs. William Randolph Hearst, Jr., and others, 1973 (Box-folder 194: 16)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to abuse of process, unauthorized practice, the Civil Rights Act, and punitive damages in Chicago and elsewhere, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 194: 17-18)
- Miscellany, 1980 (Box-folder 194: 19-20)
- Luis Kutner vs. Guerra, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 195: 1-3)
- Lake Communications Inc. vs. ICC Corporation (a Korean Corporation), 1979-1980 (Box-folder 195: 4-6)
- Financial records, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 195: 7)
- Legal research materials, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 195: 8)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to drugs in the United States and Mexico, and the question of immunity, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 195: 9-12)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 195: 13)
- Luis Kutner vs. Guerra, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 196: 1-9)
- Financial records, 1972 (Box-folder 196: 10)
- Sears Bank and Trust Company, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 196: 11-12)
- Clippings relating to Mexico, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 196: 13)
- Miscellany, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 196: 14)
- Allways International, Inc. vs. Lake Communications, Inc., 1979-1980 (Box-folder 197: 1-17)
- Luis Kutner vs. Bryan Cave, Michael Dennis, McPheeters 8 McRoberts--Miscellany, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 197: 18)
- Correspondence
  - Juan K. Kim, 1980 (Box-folder 197: 19)
  - Paul Kirby, 1980 (Box-folder 197: 20)
  - Louis M. Minotti, 1980 (Box-folder 197: 21)
  - Andrew Sigler, 1980 (Box-folder 197: 22)
  - Thomas P. Sullivan, 1980 (Box-folder 197: 23)
  - Donald J. Veverka, 1979 (Box-folder 197: 24)
- Financial records, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 197: 25-36)
- Notes, undated (Box-folder 197: 37)
- Miscellany, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 197: 38)
- Allways International, Inc. vs. Tulane Research and Investment Corporation, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 198: 1)
- Luis Kutner vs. Bryan Cave, McPheeters 8 McRoberts, and Michael Dennis, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 198: 2-5)
- Luis Kutner vs. Philip A. Demassa, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 199: 1)
- Files relating to the case of Luis Kutner vs. Bryan, Cave, McPheeters 8 McRoberts, Michael Dennis, Baker McKenzie, Allways International, Inc., and I. C. C. Korea, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 199: 2-16)
- Luis Kutner vs. Philip Demassa and Jean Guerra, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 200: 1-9)
- Luis Kutner vs. Paula Epstein a.k.a Paula Rhodes, Josephine Annesley, David M. Engelson, and Samuel Tannenbaum, 1972 (Box-folder 200: 10)
- Correspondence
  - Earl J. Thomas, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 200: 11)
  - American Red Cross, 1984 (Box-folder 201: 1)
  - Marie Bullock, 1984 (Box-folder 201: 2)
  - Max Chopnick, 1984 (Box-folder 201: 3)
  - Gaslight Ltd., 1984 (Box-folder 201: 4)
  - Adil Shahryar, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 201: 5)
  - Westview Press, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 201: 6)
  - Medical journal, 1983 (Box-folder 201: 7)
  - Journal of International Law, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 201: 8)
- Indira Gandhi, 1984 (Box-folder 201: 9)
- Iran--Violation of human rights, 1982 (Box-folder 201: 10-11)
  Includes 1 compact sound cassette recording (1) a press conference of the chief judge of the Khomeini regime, Mohammadi Gilani, and (2) an internal radio communication of the Pasdaran, undated
- Correspondence (Box 202)
  - Chicago Sun-Times, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 202: 1)
  - Helen Solem, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 202: 2)
- KenLee Enterprises International, Ltd. (Fireplace Plus), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 202: 3-7)
  Annual report, clippings, correspondence, newsletter, notes, and miscellany
- Gin-Seng products, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 202: 8-10)
  Application for trademark, brochures, certificate of registration, printed matter, and miscellany
- Miscellany, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 202: 11-12)
- Lists (Box 203)
  - Library, 1975 (Box-folder 203: 1)
  - Published articles, reviews, and schools, 1964-1971 and undated (Box-folder 203: 2)
  - Articles sent to law reviews, current law journal articles, form letters, and mailing, 1974-1977 and undated (Box-folder 203: 3)
- Writing by Luis Kutner--"The New Concept of Corporacide: Some Unpostponable Considerations" (with Burr McCloskey), undated (Box-folder 203: 4)
- Miscellany, 1981 and undated (Box-folder 203: 5-7)
- Correspondence relating to law journal articles submitted, rejected, and returned after review, and requests, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 204: 1-7)
  Includes letters relating to a collection of articles under the title: "The Legal Ecumenics of Luis Kutner"
- Lists of unpublished law journal articles by Luis Kutner, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 204: 8-11)
- Writing by Luis Kutner--"The Controversial Question of Amnesty,", undated (Box-folder 204: 12)
  Includes related correspondence, 1981
- Miscellany, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 204: 13)
- Correspondence (Box 205)
  - George B. Collins, 1972 (Box-folder 205: 1)
  - John Glenn, 1983 (Box-folder 205: 2)
  - New York University Press, 1981 (Box-folder 205: 3)
  - Northwestern Law Review, 1975 (Box-folder 205: 4)
- Lists
  - Mailing, 1973 (Box-folder 205: 5)
  - Women lawyers, undated (Box-folder 205: 6)
  - Requests for reprints, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 205: 7-8)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "Mankind vs. Mankind: The Need for a United World, Unilaw and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 205: 9)
  - "Willkie at Philadelphia: The Farce of Presidential Nominating Conventions,", undated (Box-folder 205: 10)
- Luis Kutner vs. Paula Epstein, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 205: 11-16)
- Irish Freedom Center, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 205: 17)
- Miscellany, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 205: 18)
- Correspondence (Box 206)
  - Christine Foster, 1983 (Box-folder 206: 1)
  - Donna J. Stone Pesch, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 206: 2)
  - S. Phelps Platt, Jr., 1981 (Box-folder 206: 3)
  - William C. Raines, 1971 (Box-folder 206: 4)
  - Lou Reda, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 206: 5-6)
  - Max Rosey, 1983 (Box-folder 206: 7)
  - David Lubell, 1971 (Box-folder 206: 8-9)
- Paula Epstein, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 206: 10-14)
- Mary Lupton, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 206: 15)
- Clippings and printed matter about legal issues, including jurisdiction, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 206: 16)
- Miscellany, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 206: 17-18)
- Correspondence (Box 207)
  - Jeanne Gustavo-Guerra, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 1)
  - Gustavo Guerra, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 2)
  - Cosmo Lopez, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 3)
  - John A. Mitchell, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 4-5)
  - Ron Thorpe, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 6)
  - Robert L. Page, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 7)
  - Samuel K. Skinner, 1975 (Box-folder 207: 8)
  - Earl Thomas, 1976 (Box-folder 207: 9)
- Financial records, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 10-11)
- Legal records, 1972-1979 and undated (Box-folder 207: 12-16)
  Relate to cases involving Jean and Gustavo Guerra, Mathew Whitaker, and Joseph Lord. Correspondence, notes, report, and statement
- Notes, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 207: 17-22)
- Statement, 1972 (Box-folder 207: 23)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the drug problem, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 207: 24)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 207: 25)
- Correspondence (Box 208)
  - George Collins, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 1)
  - Robert J. Spinazzola, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 2-4)
  - James J. Grogan, undated (Box-folder 208: 5)
  - Walter C. Hilger, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 208: 6)
  - Lou Reda, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 208: 7-8)
  - Earl J. Thomas, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 10)
- Jean Guerra and Philip Demassa, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 11-14)
- Notes, undated (Box-folder 208: 15)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Semitism, human rights, Soviet Jewry, and the Palestinian issue, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 208: 16-18)
- Miscellany, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 208: 19)
- Correspondence (Box 209)
  - Richard M. Daley, 1983 (Box-folder 209: 1)
  - Donna Bader Savord, 1980 (Box-folder 209: 2)
  - Donald Brittain and Barbara Sears, 1968-1979 (Box-folder 209: 3)
  - Albert Einstein, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 209: 4)
- Lawrence Freedman, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 209: 5-6)
  Suicide file
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 209: 7)
- Lawrence Freedman, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 210: 1)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "The Cult-Occult Instinct: Behavioral Ritual Deception,", undated (Box-folder 210: 2)
    Outline
  - "Marriage, Family, Divorce: Friends and Foes--The Psychiatric Profiles of Social Pathology,", undated (Box-folder 210: 3)
  - "Mortality vs. Immorality: Development of Codes of Living,", undated (Box-folder 210: 4)
  - "Repressing the Grey Menace of Depression,", undated (Box-folder 210: 5)
  - "How to Be a Wise Family,", undated (Box-folder 210: 6)
  - "Personal Emotional Freedom: Coping with Stern Reality," undated. (Box-folder 210: 7)
  - "The Dynamics of Behavioral Psychiatry,", undated (Box-folder 210: 8)
  - "The Fraud of Behavioral Communism,", undated (Box-folder 210: 9)
  - "Seeds of Madness: Psycho-Profiles of Mass Murderers,", undated (Box-folder 210: 10)
  - "Adolescence: The Relentless Bridge between the Child and the Adult,", undated (Box-folder 210: 11)
  - "Suicide: Preventing the Journey into Anguish,", undated (Box-folder 210: 12-13)
  - "Pedia-Psychiatry and the Enlightened Parent,", undated (Box-folder 210: 14)
    Notes
  - Miscellaneous outlines, undated (Box-folder 210: 15)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to mental illness, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 210: 16-20)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 210: 21)
- Correspondence (Box 211)
  - Herschel Auerbach, 1983 (Box-folder 211: 1)
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 211: 2)
  - Guy Von Dardel, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 211: 3-4)
  - Joseph M. Goldman, 1978 (Box-folder 211: 5)
  - Clyde Hall 8 Associates, 1975 (Box-folder 211: 6)
  - Ted Liss, 1973 (Box-folder 211: 7)
  - Frances Sullivant, 1972 (Box-folder 211: 8)
- National Film Board of Canada, 1978 (Box-folder 211: 9)
  Contract
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 211: 10-12)
- William C. and Elizabeth Fay, 1978 (Box-folder 211: 13)
  Last will and testament
- Legal records, 1981 (Box-folder 211: 14)
  Includes materials relating to a case of Cable News Network, Inc. vs. American Broadcasting Company, Columbia Broadcasting System, National Broadcasting Company, Ronald Reagan, James Baker III, and Larry Speaks, 1981
- Financial records, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 211: 15-21)
- William J. Lysen, 1973 (Box-folder 211: 22-23)
  Statement re: fees
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Yuri Andropov, Raoul Wallenberg and the Holocaust, higher education, human rights, the Middle East, and Soviet espionage in the United States, 1981-1983 and undated (Box-folder 211: 24-25)
- Correspondence (Box 212)
  - Michael Reisman, 1979 (Box-folder 212: 1)
  - Harold D. Lasswell, 1966-1979 (Box-folder 212: 2-3)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 212: 4-6)
  Power of attorney and related materials
- World trade, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 212: 7-13)
  Correspondence, clippings, printed matter, and materials relating to international trade of coal, oil, and food
- Clippings and printed matter about the Holocaust and Raoul Wallenberg, and human rights, 1961-1982 (Box-folder 212: 14)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 213: 1)
  - "Rights and Responsibilities at the University,", 1971
  - "The Arctic Ocean: A Contest of Sovereignty,", 1983
- Harold D. Lasswell, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 213: 2-12)
  Correspondence and other materials relating to his estate, living will, and trust
- Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America: College Retirement Equities Fund, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 213: 13)
  Affidavit, correspondence, financial records, and miscellany
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 213: 14)
- Minutes of meeting of the Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1986 (Box-folder 214: 1)
- An article by Luis Kutner, "Mankind vs. Mankind: The Need for a United World, Unilaw and World Habeas Corpus,", 1985-1986 (Box-folder 214: 2)
  Includes a letter from William J. Brennan, Jr.
- An Article by Luis Kutner, "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1985-1987 (Box-folder 214: 3)
  Includes correspondence and minutes of a meeting of the Commission for International Due Process of Law
- Articles about Luis Kutner, letters, printed matter, and miscellany, 1987-1988 and undated (Box-folder 214: 4)
- Writings by Luis Kutner--"Legal Ecumenics" (Box-folder 214: 5)
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Legacy of Mount Sinai,", 1980
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Due Process and the Judeo-Christian Tradition,", 1980
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", 1981
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace--A Proposal,", 1981
  - "Magna Carta: The Ignored Legacy of Anti-Semitism,", 1982
  - "World Habeas Corpus--Human Rights and Individual Freedom: Myth, Farce and Political Reality,", 1984
  - "Habeas Propietatem Revisited,", 1984
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1985
  - "Mankind vs. Mankind: The Need for a United World, Unilaw and World Habeas Corpus,", 1985
  - "A Convention on the Recognition of Misprison as an International Crime: A Proposal,", 1986
- Minutes of the meeting of the Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1986
- "A World Genocide Tribunal--Rampant against Future Genocide: Proposal for Planetary Preventive Measures Supplementing a Genocide--Early Warning System," article by Luis Kutner, World Habeas Corpus: Genocide and Individual Freedom, edited by Luis Kutner, 1989 and undated (Box-folder 214: 6)
  Includes letters and articles by others, including Norodom Sihanouk
- "The New International Covenant for Permanent Peace." Includes an article about Luis Kutner and a proposal by Harold Lasswell, 1989 and undated (Box-folder 214: 7)
- Article, "Revolt of Planet Earth" by Luis Kutner, legal documents, press release, and printed matter, 1986-1989 and undated (Box-folder 214: 8)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 215: 1)
  - "World Habeas Corpus,", 1962
  - "I the Lawyer,", 1966
- Cambodia--Prince Samdech Norodom Sihanouk, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 216: 1-4)
  Bulletins, correspondence, clippings, printed matter, and miscellany
- Cambodia, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 217: 1-6)
- Cambodia, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 218: 1)
  Bulletins, clippings, and printed matter
- Cambodia, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 219: 1-3)
  Bulletins
- Fabio K. Banegura vs. Nacole V. Taylor, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 219: 4-5)
- Temple Mount, Jerusalem, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 220: 1-3)
- Andrei Sakharov, 1976-1986 (Box-folder 220: 4-7)
  Brochure, clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and related materials
- Terrorism, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 221: 1-5)
  Mostly clippings
- Miscellany, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 221: 6)
- South Africa (Box 222)
  - Winston P. Nagan, 1988 (Box-folder 222: 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, and report on the comprehensive Anti-Apartheid Act of 1986
  - Permanent South African Mission to the United Nations, 1988 (Box-folder 222: 2)
  - South African organizations--Ann Micou, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 222: 3)
    U.S. professional association inventory relating to black South Africans, memoranda, printed matter, and working paper
  - United Nations organizations regarding South Africa, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 222: 4)
    Letter, memoranda, and printed matter
  - United Nations office, Geneva--H. Kailau, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 222: 5)
  - Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany, 1972-1988 (Box-folder 222: 6-7)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 223: 1-6)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 223: 7)
  - Correspondence (Box 224)
    - Joseph Cardinal Bernardin, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 224: 1)
    - George Burditt, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 2)
    - Michael R. Christie, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 224: 3)
    - John Dugard, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 4)
    - Freedom House, 1987 (Box-folder 224: 5)
    - Norman Hill and others, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 6)
    - International Law Association, 1987 (Box-folder 224: 7)
    - A. L. Manley and Christian W. v. M. Kamp, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 8)
    - Eugene Antonio Marino, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 9)
    - Michael H. Posner, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 224: 10)
    - John Sengstacke, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 11)
    - Helen Suzman, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 12)
    - Desmond Tutu, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 13)
    - David Welsh, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 14)
    - Miscellany, 1988 (Box-folder 224: 15)
  - Clippings and printed matter relating to apartheid and human rights, the International Labor Organization, and the U.S. Senate resolution regarding the banning of political activity, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 224: 16-19)
  - Miscellany, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 224: 20)
  - Christian Kamp, 1988 (Box-folder 225: 1-2)
    Bulletin, clippings, correspondence, legal record, memoranda, printed matter, and report
  - Nelson Mandela, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 225: 3)
  - Byron W. Charlton, 1988 (Box-folder 225: 4)
  - Lane Kirkland (AFL-CIO), 1988 (Box-folder 225: 5)
    Brochure and correspondence
  - Mike Lasco (AFL-CIO), undated (Box-folder 225: 6)
  - United Mine Workers of America, 1988 (Box-folder 225: 7)
  - Clippings and printed matter about apartheid, individual rights, release of Nelson Mandela, terrorism, and world habeas corpus, 1979-1988 (Box-folder 225: 8)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 226: 1)
  - "I, the Lawyer,", 1966
  - "The New International Covenant for Permanent Peace,", 1989
  - List of chapters in different volumes of "Legal Ecumenics" and letters to Luis Kutner from Israel W. Charny and Jakob Th. Möller, 1990 and undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Sanctity of Individual Freedom,", undated (Box-folder 226: 2)
  - "The Roots of World Habeas Corpus,", 1980
- Miscellaneous printed matter, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 226: 3)
  Includes issue of Denver Journal of International Law and Policy dedicated to Luis Kutner, and information on nuclear resistance and the peace movement
- Letters and printed matter, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 227: 1-8)
  Relates to human rights violations in Iraq, global justice, and world habeas corpus
- Writings by Luis Kutner and other material, 1962-1986 and undated (Box-folder 227: 9)
  - "Statute of the World Court of Public Opinion,", undated
  - "World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1985
  - "Mankind vs. Mankind: The Need for a United World, Unilaw and World Habeas Corpus,", 1985
  - "A Convention of the Recognition of Misprison as an International Crime,", 1986
  - Minutes of meeting of the Commission for International Due Process of Law, submitted by Luis Kutner, 1986
  - "The Revolt of Planet Earth,", 1986
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, individual justice, legal cases, living wills, right-to-die, and world habeas corpus, 1965-1989 (Box-folder 227: 10-12)
- Miroslav Medved, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 228: 1-2)
- Moot court--Philip C. Jessup International Law Moot Court Competition, 1989 (Box-folder 228: 3)
  Correspondence, index, notes, and related materials
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the Medvid affair, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 228: 4)
- Miscellany, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 228: 5)
- Human rights, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 229: 1-2)
  Annual report, articles, correspondence, printed matter, and statement. Relates to genocide, torture and other human rights issues in the Arab states, Armenia, Israel, and Turkey
- Miscellaneous literature, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 229: 3)
- Ronald I. Pritikin, 1956-1990 (Box-folder 230: 1)
- European Council on Human Rights, 1959-1975 (Box-folder 230: 2-3)
  Research materials
- Ronald Pritikin, 1971-1990 (Box-folder 231: 1)
- World Advocates Center, 1968-1981 (Box-folder 231: 2-3)
  Clippings, correspondence, newsletter, notes, printed matter, report on refugees, and miscellany
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 232: 1)
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", undated
  - "Defense of the Tolerance, Liberty, and Abundance in America,", 1939
  - "Unfair Comment: A Warning to News Media,", 1962
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", 1965
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967